<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>The Breezer&#x27;s Brew</title>
    <link href="https://breezersbrew.org/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://breezersbrew.org" />
    <updated>2024-05-03T23:55:19+06:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Uzayer Masud</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://breezersbrew.org</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Sparkling Water </title>
        <author>
            <name>Ariana Hossain</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://breezersbrew.org/sparkling-water/"/>
        <id>https://breezersbrew.org/sparkling-water/</id>
            <category term="Literature"/>
            <category term="Fiction"/>

        <updated>2024-05-03T23:36:40+06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Do I even like strawberries? Cassandra doesn't remember liking them. She remembers eating them, and she remembers sharing them with Alice. She knows she owns several strawberry themed dresses and shirts and pencils. She knows that Alice has given her a strawberry-shaped bag because of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do I even like strawberries?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cassandra doesn't remember liking them. She remembers eating them, and she remembers sharing them with Alice. She knows she owns several strawberry themed dresses and shirts and pencils. She knows that Alice has given her a strawberry-shaped bag because of it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, for the life of her, she can't remember liking them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With a sigh, she takes a sip of her strawberry milkshake. It isn't terrible, but she just wishes she could just </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">remember</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She's fairly confident that Alice likes strawberries. That might explain it. Anything and everything Alice likes, she likes. They were supposed to be a duo after all, and all good duos are supposed to be similar to one another. Alice likes strawberries, so Cassandra likes strawberries. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Cassie!”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cassandra startles as a blur of yellow wraps itself around her shoulders. She almost falls under the weight, and she needs to grip her milkshake tighter so it doesn't fall out of her hand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She smiles at Alice, more out of habit than anything. Alice has a strawberry clip in her hair that's helping to keep the bangs out of her eyes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She's relatively sure that Alice likes strawberries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Alice,” she nods, a smile pasted on her face. “How are you?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I'm just wonderful</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> How are </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">you </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">doing?” Alice's smile is bright. Cassandra doesn't think she's ever seen it not be bright.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She tries to adjust her smile to be as bright as Alice's. They're supposed to be a good duo.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I'm alright.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She isn't, and something is bothering her, but she can't put her finger on it. She does her best not to look like she's lost. Cassandra takes another sip of her milkshake. It tastes a little wrong.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice holds onto her arm, the one that's not holding onto the milkshake, and they both start walking. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Her friend is talking about something, but she's only half paying attention to it. She smiles and laughs at the correct times as Alice continues her rambling. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Something seems wrong to her. But why should it? The weather is pleasantly cool and it's perfect for walking. She's with Alice, who seems so happy to be here with her.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Look!” Alice stops in her steps. She drops Cassandra's arm and points at a tree.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cassandra stops as well and looks at where Alice is pointing. “I don't see anything.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“No, see! Look at the top branches, Cassie.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She squints, though that doesn't help her much. A small, almost unnoticeable movement catches her eye.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Is that a squirrel?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Yes!” Her friend's smile is just so </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">bright.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Like the Sun. “Isn't it so cute?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I guess so.” She isn't really that fond of animals. “It's very small.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Yes, and it's just adorable and so sweet. Don't you wish you could just hug it?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cassandra nods at that, her smile a bit half-hearted. She really doesn't, but that's fine.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They continue walking after that. Everything seems so normal and fine. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, what </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> bothering her?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She tries to brush it off as nothing. But, she knows it isn't and that something is wrong.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She replays the conversation in her head. It's when she recalls that Alice referred to her as “Cassie” that she realizes what's wrong. She doesn't like that. Her name is Cassandra, not Cassie.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Please don't call me that. </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Could I ask you to do something for me, Alice?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Of course, what is it?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Could you not call me Cassie, please? I don't like being called that.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice's reaction is almost immediate, the brightness in her fades, and she pouts at Cassandra. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Oh, but it's such a cute name, and it suits you so well! Plus, I've been calling you that for years now. Do I really have to stop?”</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, please.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, she wouldn't want to be a bad friend, would she?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Well… I suppose it's alright.” Her voice is hesitant. She doesn't feel like it's alright, and it's obvious in her speech. “Maybe call me that less frequently, then?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Her friend evidently doesn't notice.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“No promises, but I'll try!”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice smiles and she tries to match it with one of her own. They continue walking, and the conversation resumes. She takes another sip of her milkshake as they do. It tastes like ash in her mouth.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As they walk, her friend reaches out to hold her hand again. She loves Alice (it goes without saying, really, who doesn't love Alice?) but she despises skin to skin contact. Her love for her friend doesn't cancel out her repulsion to touch, unfortunately. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She tries to bear it a little longer. She tries to distract herself by taking another sip of her milkshake. It doesn't help. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She manages a few more steps before she's had enough.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Is… is it alright if you don't hold my hand?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice pouts again, her hand tightening on hers. She feels a slight sense of panic rise up. Oh, she's made Alice upset, hasn't she?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She's so </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">stupid</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It's such a small thing, isn't it? Alice does so much for her. The least she can do is hold her hand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cassie wouldn't want to be a bad friend.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice opens her mouth, possibly to protest, but before she can, Cassie shushes her.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Actually, I-I suppose it's alright. It's fine, really, I'm sorry. I don't know what I was thinking. It's fine.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice tilts her head, a look of confusion taking over her features. She's about to speak again, but then she shuts her mouth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“‘Kay, no worries.” Alice's smile is warm again.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cassie tries to smile back, but it's shaky and uncertain at best. After a split second of hesitation, she tightens her hold on her friend's hand. She means it to be comforting for one of them, at least.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cassie takes another sip of her milkshake. It tastes rotten as she swallows it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She's fine and she's alright. She's just being a good friend, is all. All good friends have to make sacrifices.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They continue walking. Alice mentions this one café that opened recently and how it's apparently amazing. And she's also getting really hungry so wouldn't Cassie </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">please</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> go to the café with her?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course she would.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice looks so happy at her agreement that Cassie smiles back. Hers is a pale imitation of Alice's brightness. A moon to her sun.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, just like any duo, they're similar enough.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“D’you mind if I take a sip of your milkshake?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She hesitates for a brief second before shaking her head. It doesn't taste good, but Alice mentioned that she was hungry. She holds it out for her. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice leans in and takes a sip. Her eyes brighten, and she takes another one.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It's really sweet, but it's also really good. I like it a lot. Thanks, Cassie.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Don't worry about it.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That's a bit strange. But, people can have different tastes. Sure, Cassie and Alice are supposed to be a duo, but duos should also have some differences between each other.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even so, Cassie takes another sip of her milkshake. The strawberries taste like they've been left out in the sun to rot. The flavour sticks to the back of her throat as she swallows it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice and her are different, but she hopes it's not in the ways that really matter. She takes another sip of her milkshake and then another.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It's probably an acquired taste. If she just drinks more and more of it, it's bound to taste sweet at one point. After all, Alice liked it. So she should like it too.</span></p>
<hr>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The girl resumes her conversation afterwards, pausing only briefly to adjust the hair clip keeping her hair out of her eyes. The focus of the story remains on her even as it concludes.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Nazrul&#x27;s Immaculate Rizz - My Experience with Bangla and Internet Culture</title>
        <author>
            <name>Uzayer Masud</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://breezersbrew.org/nazruls-immaculate-rizz-my-experience-with-bangla-and-internet-culture/"/>
        <id>https://breezersbrew.org/nazruls-immaculate-rizz-my-experience-with-bangla-and-internet-culture/</id>
            <category term="Personal Narrative"/>
            <category term="Literature"/>

        <updated>2024-03-05T23:09:14+06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    My relationship with the language I was born with has changed significantly over time, and this particular metamorphosis has come at a time of self-actualisation as I grow into adulthood. I strongly believe that language shapes the way we perceive the world. There is the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My relationship with the language I was born with has changed significantly over time, and this particular metamorphosis has come at a time of self-actualisation as I grow into adulthood.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I strongly believe that language shapes the way we perceive the world. There is the English I speak and breathe, then there's the broken business English that my father uses to communicate emotionally difficult confessions because Bangla strikes too hard on the heart. There is the Bangla I hated so strongly in fourth grade and the Bangla the people in my life speak with patient, observant love. All of these languages in their many </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">faces coexist in my life and my perception changes with every one of them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A couple of months back, I wiped the dust off my mother's dying hard drive to upload it to Google. After shifting through random wedding photos and quite a few birthdays, I found an old video of me speaking to my parents. I was four years old at the time and talked a lot. What I did notice was that my speech was entirely in Bangla.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a child, the media I consumed (over which I had no control) consisted of UNICEF's Meena cartoons and children's poetry my parents would make me learn. Another major source of content were the stories that my aunt, a cultural anthropologist, would read to me. Two years later, I would have a music teacher who would teach me how to play harmonium and sing Rabindra Sangeet, all of which I have now forgotten.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It seems very impossible now. I have to put in a lot more effort to speak entirely in Bangla, or even read it. I genuinely try, but constantly find myself unable to express my thoughts the way I want to. English has become the language that I think in and exercise so much control over. I understand its tones, its nuances and cultural references. In my mind, it feels like home. It was the language that accepted me, or understood me in an intolerant society. That allowed me to exist as more than my mother's thinly veiled "do you have a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">different</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> type of problem?" - the concept of queerness being so shocking that she never said it out loud.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I hated learning Bangla when I started going to school. I was mostly guilted and shamed into it for the entire time I had to learn it there. We had only one class for it </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">and had very little exposure and practice with its written form. On the other hand, English literature classes had books so pretty they never felt like studying for me. Bangla had stories written in verbose words I was too young to comprehend. (This is why Shakespeare should be taught in tenth grade, not seventh).</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">তোমার নিজের মাতৃভাষা তুমি শিখবা না?<br></span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Won't you learn your own mother's tongue?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I write in English, I have verisimilitude, the "truthiness" that makes you believe that what I'm saying really is true. In English, I have flow, and more importantly, experience. I have a sense of belonging. Unfortunately, with Bangla, I have none of that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I find myself having cultural clashes with my mother, someone I have been living with for the past 18 years. I feel a sort of guilt and disconnect. I struggle to understand her completely. I write unfinished poetry in a language she was beaten into memorising. Despite that, through many conversations and introspection, I have narrowed down the reason to the fact that we as a generation simply no longer occupy the cultural or literary spaces that our parents did.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instagram and TikTok (far, far more than Facebook), are a sort of abstract neighbourhood that we hang out in when we have time. As a former 14 year old, I understand the lack of demand to learn the language because Bangla simply isn't how we communicate on the internet. Our generation has moulded English into further sub-dialects that don't belong to an area and introduced nuances that would be indiscernible to the outsider who has no concept of what "rizz¹" is. Teenagers in the 80's did not speak in fluent, well articulated sentences and they will certainly not start now. Language will continue to evolve as long as people evolve. Languages are fluid and English has changed, Bangla, at least for us, has not.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This abstract space that we occupy is an oversaturated representation of reality in the middle of the AI revolution. It is not a real place yet it is the unshakeable town square of our generation. It is the perfect place for us to lose our sense of self. In our hyper-targeted, curated feed, we see so many people in there from around the world (mostly from the US) and so many cultures (again, US immigrants). Our desire to fit in contradicts heavily with the notion of learning a language we speak well but cannot write properly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our consumerist, secular, modern life leaves very little scope to break from the perceived norm. The way we have built up our lives in my particular demographic, has left no room for original thought, or a moment of calm. Relaxation is essentially consuming hyper-curated media (that sometimes create echo-hells) on our phones, and all of this is in English. Language shapes thought, and thought shapes culture. And that is the one that we internalise and inhibit.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On another observation, my brother is six years younger than me, on the cusp of adolescence. His clashes with my mother remind me exactly of the miscommunication that I faced when I was younger, precisely due to this cultural disconnect. Only I had no one who would understand me at home back then.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I noticed a friend of his, Samara, shortening her name to Sam, and eventually changing it to Samantha on Instagram. A complete deviation from the original Bangla. This anglicisation of her name was deliberate, yet very much a subconscious move to fit in with a growing global world. Another attempt at avoiding social rejection.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My goal is not to critique social media but to provide a window for understanding and consolation into the growing cultural disconnect that I have with my parents, and that the vast majority of my generation and peers have had.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is also important that we recognize what the world is as of now. After 200 years of British rule over Bengal, and English being the language of the ruling class, it has been ingrained into our collective consciousness that English is the superior tongue.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We also lose more of our own culture as we try to fit the mould of another, and our literature reflects that. Rabindranath's writing has incredible undertones of femininity in it, despite him being a bearded man. The concept of gender being intrinsically fluid in nature is prevalent all throughout his work. It is not black and white. His characters are androgynous and the ideas are far more freeing: a break from the monotony we face with the English (precisely due to the church and the state deeming all of this as savage demonic ideas from an uncivilised people).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He was from a wealthy family that had supported the humanities for generations. He learnt English well enough to translate his own work, ultimately winning himself the Nobel Prize in Literature and exposing Bengali literature to the West. By comparison, Kazi Nazrul was born to Bengal's poorest of the poor. He had no interest in English. His works were later crudely translated, which the then British government used to label him as an anti-British, anti-government rebel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">English was, and still is, the lingua franca for the world we live in. Ignoring it would be a grave mistake but not learning Bangla as well provides a hole for us to fall into wherein we lose our identity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Very recently I have started to reconnect with the culture I grew up in. I started watching movies by Satyajit Ray, and listening to Nazrul Geeti (which I wish I understood as well as I understand Sylvia Plath or Arundhati Roy).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because after all this time it gives me a handle to a part of my psyche I had forgotten. Self-identity has always been something every person spends their adolescence and perhaps a fair part of their twenties trying to find and establish. I enjoy listening to this music, despite not understanding it fully. I love watching these movies. It gives me a space to occupy in the abstract neighbourhood I call home.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">সৃজন ছন্দে আনন্দে নাচো নটরাজ<br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">হে মহকাল প্রলয়–তাল ভোলো ভোলো।।<br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">- কাজী নজরুল</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oh Notoraj!<br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dance to the joy of creation<br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bury your fervour of destruction<br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> - Kazi Nazrul</span></p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rizz ¹ - 2020s internet lingo for one’s ability to attract another person in a romantic sense. Short for “charisma”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Notoraj ² - The deity of dance. A depiction of the Hindu god Shiva as the divine cosmic dancer.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Anxiety</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fahmid Rahman</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://breezersbrew.org/anxiety/"/>
        <id>https://breezersbrew.org/anxiety/</id>
        <media:content url="https://breezersbrew.org/media/posts/6/anxiety.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Personal Narrative"/>
            <category term="Literature"/>

        <updated>2024-03-04T22:19:16+06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://breezersbrew.org/media/posts/6/anxiety.jpg" alt="" />
                    Breathe. I had to breathe. My lungs felt empty and incapable with each and every breath. It felt like there was no oxygen left for me. Panic had me immobilised. An abrupt gasp of air fled my mouth; I struggled to inhale. The air was&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://breezersbrew.org/media/posts/6/anxiety.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Breathe. I had to breathe.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My lungs felt empty and incapable with each and every breath. It felt like there was no oxygen left for me. Panic had me immobilised. An abrupt gasp of air fled my mouth; I struggled to inhale. The air was caught in my throat, choking me, stuck like it had been ensnared by a python.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The faces of people around me warped into blurred effigies, as if I was looking into the world through a mosaic screen. Inexplicable heat surged through my body. The streaks of sweat that ran down my forehead acted as a constant reminder of my own weakness.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It felt like I was submerged. Not in the shallow waters of a lake or some pond in a park, but drowning in the most frigid, crushing depths. Enough to make me want to keel over and vomit out my insides. A rapid waterfall of thoughts cascaded out of every cavern in my mind, each fleeting impulse ricocheting to and from the nerves in my body, screaming at me to do something. I longed for the release, for the words to leave my throat and for my body to move. I yearned to throw up bile into the toilet, choking it out. To feel tears trickle down my cheeks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But I couldn’t move or do anything. I lost control of my own body and was benched into some obscure corner of my psyche, forced to spectate myself as a stringless marionette. So I stood. And I stared. My vision shrunk and faded like the chorus of a lullaby, steadily hushing quieter and quieter until it was barely as faint as a whisper, all the while my heart pulsed faster to the point I couldn’t tell the difference between one beat and the next. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At that point, my consciousness blinked out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That was my first encounter with the overwhelming dread of a panic attack. But compared to what I went through trying to recuperate, it might as well have only been a glimpse. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After another episode, a day spent at home recovering and some back and forth contemplation, I took the initiative to tell my family everything I kept from them so far. It was difficult. Since I was opening up for the first time, I was afraid of being misunderstood or even accused of inflating my problems. Even if it was irrational, a part of me thought everything might just be my own fault.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So when they listened, without any interruptions, without disregarding anything I said, I saw a bit of hope. That sliver of trust was precious. We talked for a long time afterwards and decided it would be best to seek professional advice. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sitting in the midst of ivory walls, I faced a row of iridescent curtains and beside them a scarlet leather armchair. The psychiatrist slumped in it, scrutinising the piece of paper in his hand with tense creases etched into his forehead. I tried to smile, but my skin had gone stiff. I felt dense and subdued. He looked at my parents first, and then peered straight at me before declaring his diagnosis with a sigh. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “You have social anxiety disorder.” </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I remember his expression as he said it. No trace of suspense or worry, or even a sense of gravity as the words escaped from his lips and disappeared with the fall wind wafting through the curtains. He appeared unusually calm—even exhausted. Not the detached coolness of an indifferent stranger or the air of levity associated with laughing it off as a bad attitude, but just simple weariness. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It made sense. He had probably made the same assessment for loads of patients. Social anxiety was one of the most common forms of anxiety disorder after all. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It wasn't just timidity from the beginning. Involuntarily, I would freeze up in front of others, back even when I was still in elementary school. I still remember when my teacher asked me to recite the 4-times table but I couldn’t, not because I didn't know but because I wasn't capable of speaking in front of my classmates. My school report said I showed no interest. I would get spooked and stumble all over my words when met with the prospect of a conversation, eventually earning the badge of an outcast for my habit of mumbling incoherently and forming a rift between me and my peers that I could never understand how to bridge.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Somewhere along the way, I learnt it was easier to not speak up at all. Or look anyone in the eyes. I had no desire to interact with the outside world.  I was perfectly content with it. I have only ever been an enigma everybody wanted to crack.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I didn’t think I could ever truly conquer it. The feeling of being constantly watched. The part of me that longs to feel significant is the same part of me that insists I'm irredeemably dreadful. I wanted to be seen and acknowledged as a person who was in pain and struggling to survive in my own unwarranted way. The fear of being different. The terror of everyone’s eyes cutting more wounds into my mind that wouldn’t heal, of reopening those old scars of being rejected and left out because of not conforming. I sought reassurance. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The thought of someone seeing me vulnerable shakes me to my core. I was afraid of change. I found a way to cope with my feelings, and I was terrified of what I might find if I relinquished it. Every time I bump into someone accidentally, a panicked shiver still dances up my spine and I ruminate on the myriad ways it could’ve been avoided. I find it impossible to eat in front of someone else. The thought of them judging me for having crumbs on my face makes it unbearable. Thinking of anyone seeing me doing anything embarrassing feels unendurable. It makes me want to hide deep in an uninhabitable mountain range, far away from the prying stares of other people. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just like that, life used to play out like a fragrant but repetitive trance, with me always trying to conceal myself. I was baffled by the mundane yet destructive impulses that had wreaked havoc on my life. Always praying to not be noticed, yet yearning for connection at the same time. I was convinced that I was lacking something crucial within myself. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">But this time, I wanted to find and acknowledge it for myself. I desperately wanted to be let out of this cage. That brief glimmer of trust I experienced when my family listened, and everything they did to try and help me, I wanted to hold onto that tiny ember of hope as much as I could and use it. So I did. Taking the first step to approach someone was terrifying. Most of the time, I could barely force a sentence or two out before being written off as strange.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite that, people reached out to me. They eagerly helped me tear down the walls I erected brick by brick. I saw a light then. So brilliant and warm that instead of retreating into my old shadows, I ran towards it for the first time in my life. Joy echoed through me like the glorious finishing verse of an invigorating ballad. It told me that even if I wouldn’t be understood, there was no need for me to isolate myself any more. For once, I had a chance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since then, I’ve learnt that people are not predators ready to ambush me at a moment’s notice the second I let my guard down. Not everything needs to be optimised. I no longer punish myself as harshly as I used to every time I screw up. I'm glad that slowly but surely, I'm getting better, and every step along that journey takes me somewhere new and teaches me more about who I am.</span></p>
<p>Co-written by Namira Aiyana Rahman</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Ignorance is Bliss</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shadit Rahaman</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://breezersbrew.org/ignorance-is-bliss/"/>
        <id>https://breezersbrew.org/ignorance-is-bliss/</id>
        <media:content url="https://breezersbrew.org/media/posts/5/ignorance-is-bliss.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Literature"/>
            <category term="Dialogue"/>

        <updated>2024-03-04T22:16:43+06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://breezersbrew.org/media/posts/5/ignorance-is-bliss.jpg" alt="" />
                    Me: Is this thing working? It took a lot of time for me to get my dad to let me borrow it, you know. DO NOT BREAK I- *Static* Quinn: I GOT IT. Jeez, man. Chill out. It's an old recorder, not a diamond ring.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://breezersbrew.org/media/posts/5/ignorance-is-bliss.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Me:</em><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is this thing working? It took a lot of time for me to get my dad to let me borrow it, you know. DO NOT BREAK I-  </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">*Static*</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Quinn:</em><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I GOT IT. Jeez, man. Chill out. It's an old recorder, not a diamond ring. So, do you want to start or not?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Me:</em><br>Yeah. Sorry, it's just that my dad loves this thing more than anything else at our house. Well, maybe except the cat.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Quinn:</em><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anyway, so this is our first tape for serious topics. We’re bored and it’s the winter holidays. Might as well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Me:</em><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Okay so uh, what were we talking about again?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Quinn:</em><br>How ignoring, keeping your problems aside OR “running from” one’s problems- don’t always end up making things worse. Sometimes, it can actually help with dealing with them to some extent. I believe in that notion, unlike Harlow over here.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Me:</em><br>Usually you have a knack for being right, but you are completely and utterly in the wrong here. People running from their problems is the reason for thousands upon thousands of people making things worse. Letting a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">perhaps</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> small issue grow into something terrible. Something consuming. Something monstrous in their subconscious until it's too big to contain and it comes rushing out like an endless torrent of water during a flood. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Quinn:</em><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I like your funny words magic man, but no that’s not how it works for quite a lot of people I know personally. Like, even me. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Specifically</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, me. Sure, let's get into this.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Me:<br></em>Permission to absolutely wreck you in the battle of words and wits?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Quinn:</em><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Generously granted, not that you’ll be able to anyway. Other than that, let me emphasize on what I mean. Let me use myself as an example, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">again</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Okay so imagine this, you just got dumped by a girlfriend who was with you for more than fifteen months. How would you react? Let me tell you how YOU would react. Probably cry and in the end try to stay friends. What’d I do to deal with my broken heart? Hmph Easy. Just stop talking to anyone associated with her for a bit. Let the intense pain ease over time. Try my best to not think about her. Move on with life, you know? See how not dealing with that issue of her dumping me can work out. Instead of moving through the pain, wading through the ocean of heartache and broken self-esteem. Just don’t. Go away from it. In fact, forget it exists. Simple.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Me:</em><br>Well, you’re probably right about what I’d do. Even though what you surmised it to is very, VERY oversimplified. To make a point from my end imagine this for a change. Due to you never confronting your issues with you being dumped, you end up not being completely over the breakup and let’s say she gets married sometime in the future. How would you feel? Probably would need to deal with it then. Especially if you’re somehow invited to that wedding and your friends are going. At that point, it will all come crashing down. Instead of it being a wade through pain, it’ll be a tsunami of agony. You’ll end up crippling yourself. It might break you for a long time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Quinn:</em><br>Okay you may have a point there, Harlow. I can see what you mean because it has happened to me too. Like when we had those small sessions for after lockdown, remember? It’s a bit like counseling but not really. It felt like a support group. I don’t remember what exactly caused it but something that they were pressing on opened up a very old wound for me and I went on a pretty bad spiral. Went on to unravel a lot of wound up issues and other repressed stuff. Ended up making a few, uh, bad decisions. Not a good night that one.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Me:</em><br>See what I mean? Ignorance isn’t bliss. It's just putting off a problem to marinate until it seasons into an even worse problem. It is a very bad way of dealing with it in my opinion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Quinn:</em><br>You say that and you’re valid but only to an extent.  Don’t you think that the ability to go without having the risk of the problem ruining things in the present era is a bigger plus than having to potentially face it in the future? Not to mention, even if it's worse, the fact that you have had the time in between gives you a chance to be a better you. A more rational you with the skills needed to deal with such a problem. It’s a high-risk-high reward play the way I see it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Me:</em><br>WEL-</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">*Static rumbling*</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">*Rapid banging*</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Quinn:</em><br>IS THIS THING OKAY? TAKE IT BACK TO YOUR DAD! IT’S SMOKING BR-</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">*Static*</span></i></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Home</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ayesha Sharmin Hossain</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://breezersbrew.org/home-2/"/>
        <id>https://breezersbrew.org/home-2/</id>
        <media:content url="https://breezersbrew.org/media/posts/4/home.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Personal Narrative"/>
            <category term="Literature"/>

        <updated>2024-03-04T22:10:13+06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://breezersbrew.org/media/posts/4/home.jpg" alt="" />
                    I come from rich fertile lands threaded through with ribbons of blue-green water. I come from where crows mourn their dead under Poinciana trees and badgers scamper through wild sugarcane, tiny pawprints left like memories in the dirt. Or as my mother calls the long&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://breezersbrew.org/media/posts/4/home.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I come from rich fertile lands threaded through with ribbons of blue-green water. I come from where crows mourn their dead under Poinciana trees and badgers scamper through wild sugarcane, tiny pawprints left like memories in the dirt. Or as my mother calls the long grass in her native tongue - </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">kashful</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. I come from concrete jungles that never go silent and I come from a penitentiary made up of people and their judgements.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don’t</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> really</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> know where I come from. I don’t know where I belong. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">My hand wrapped tightly around the door handle, I stare at my home of 12 years, eyes trailing over the familiar silhouettes of the couch my grandma spends her evenings on, watching tv, the family portraits hung up on the wall, the book shelf stuffed to the brim with poetry books at the end of the hall, a glimpse of my grandpa’s study, its door slightly ajar. I think I've forgotten how to breathe. Or perhaps I'm holding my breath for something. Anything. Nothing.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I try to commit every single detail to memory, eyes darting around, starving and attempting to devour every single hue and shade and line and curve and cement them all in the folds of my mind. I feel lost. Unanchored. I don’t know when I’ll be back. Two months? Three? A year? Half a decade? Never? I mutter prayers under my breath to whatever god will listen, begging, pleading to be allowed to keep the details safe in my head. That time would be kind and let me remember everything as if I had never left. I don’t want to go. I don’t want to stay. I don’t know where I belong. But the plane ticket is on the dining table and like Robert Frost put it - “Nothing gold can stay.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I can’t feel my own face when I pull the front door shut, standing there on my doorstep. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">doorstep. I’m homesick and I haven’t even left yet. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I come from a cacophony of laughter at dinner. I come from bickering friends sitting on staircases. I come from nights spent on dewey grass outside my father’s childhood home, staring at the night sky ravaged by light pollution. I come from rainy days spent sitting on the roof, in awe of the petrichor hanging in the air. I come from home. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hiraeth. The longing for a home that never existed. Except for me that’s not true. I miss things that exist as concepts.  I don’t miss my house. I don’t miss my room. I miss the miasmatic blanket of nostalgia resting on everything. Home isn’t the blue building on road number two. They forgot to tell us home could be everything. What you know, what you feel, what you hear, what you see. Home is my best friend's smile and the smell of my mom’s cooking on the weekends and the song my brother plays on repeat on cloudy days and the school library and my sister’s arms and the frown of my aunt as she watches me trip on a flat surface and try to act like nothing happened. Home is anything that feels like it. And I'm starting to think like Alice in wonderland, I might have grown too big to fit here.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was 7, wanting to grow up as fast as possible, in awe of the adult world. But here I am, at the edge of 17. And I want nothing more than to find the remote control and hit freeze-frame on life. Not rewind, not forward. Freeze. I want to live in this moment for the rest of eternity. Because in this moment, I'm still home. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
